Braswell Kenneth Azu Junior (Software Engineer)

I am a Software Engineer with experience in solution design and implementation of technical software projects. Exploration is one of the things which makes me keep learning and growing. I have an interest in building, designing and animating user interfaces. I seek to develop, innovate and make the world a better place through software.

Domain Knowledge : Software Engineering / User Interface / User Experience Design.

Tech Stack - Javascript / TypeScript [React.js (Next.js / Remix / Gatsby) / Node.js / React Native, Vue] , CSS [PostCss / Sass / Scss / Tailwind Css], Golang, Flutter

Database - MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, SQLite

API Specs - REST, Graphql, gRPC

Infrastructure - Docker, AWS, GCP

Continuous Integration - Github Actions, Jenkins

Languages: English / French (Elementary Level).

Professional Experience

July 1, 2023 - Present: Software Engineer, Infinanze Technologies, US (Remote / Freelancing).

- Implement frontend web applications and websites.
- Suggest and plan solutions with the UI/UX team.
- Collaborate with the backend team to integrate APIs to make functional frontend applications.
- Planning and bridging the gap between enterprise applications with simple and user friendly UI.

April, 2022 - August, 2024 : Software Engineer, Morlan Technologies, Ghana (Remote / Freelancing).

- Plan solutions for software projects.
- Design and implement backend APIs for web and mobile applications.
- Implement frontend web applications.
- Collaborated with teammates to implement the <u>Carbazza Project</u>.
- Implement mobile solutions.

November 1, 2022 - September, 2023 : Software Engineer (National Service), Solar Taxi, Accra (Ghana).

- Plan solutions for software projects.
- Design and implement backend APIs for web and mobile applications.
- Collaborate with team members to improve existing systems by refactoring old legacy code.
- Implement frontend web applications for the Wote Project.

April 20, 2021 - November 12, 2021 : Software Engineer (Internship), The Hive, Kumasi (Ghana).

- Design User Interfaces to be implemented into mobile for the frontend and mobile application teams.
- Collaborated with team members to implement the Hive Institute platform.
- Shadowed team engineers to learn new skills.

Sep 14, 2018 - Present : Freelance Software Developer

- Build websites and web applications for institutions and startups with the sole responsibility of ensuring clients are satisfied and requirements are met.

Education

- B.Sc Computer Science and Engineering - University of Mines and Technology (2022).

References: Would be made available on request.

Contact and Address

linkedin.com/in/braswell-kenneth-870827192 | github.com/braswelljr | braswellkenneth7@gmail.com | braswelljr | +233500181106 | +233540732749